https://www.stentec.com/en/en/privacy-statement

-->
Search ...
NewsE-mail list
Signup for our newsletterStentec news
NewsDevelopers BlogWinGPSWinGPS seriesWinGPS specificationsFor Windows
WinGPS 5 LiteWinGPS 5 NavigatorWinGPS 5 ProWinGPS 5 VoyagerFor Android
WinGPS Marine LiteWinGPS MarineWinGPS Marine PlusFor iOS
WinGPS MarineWinGPS Marine PlusService Card
WinGPS Service CardChartsChart overviewDKW Inland waters
DKW The NetherlandsDKW Friese merenDKW AmsterdamDKW BiesboschDKW BelgiumDKW Northern FranceDKW Southern FranceDKW Northeast GermanyDKW Northwest GermanyDKW Southwest GermanyDKW Rhine and MoselleDKW Danube 1-WestDKW Danube 2-CentralDKW Danube 3-EastDKW Coastal waters
DKW 1800 seriesDKW UK1 English & Scottish EastcoastDKW German BightDKW German Baltic coastDKW Imray seriesDKW Delius Klasing seriesNV-Verlag seriesExclusive for Android
Subscription - DKW the NetherlandsChart appsOther
ADAC Marina GuideHardwarePeripheralsAIS adviceSimulatorsSail Simulator 5Motorboat SimulatorShopDownloadsSupportDownloadsDocumentationAvailability GRIB filesFrequently asked questions - FAQ
WinGPS 5WinGPS Marine (Android)WinGPS Marine (iOS)Installation help
WinGPS 5 (Windows)WinGPS Marine (Android)Tips
Offline installation DKW charts (Windows)Installation ENC charts (Windows)Connecting SD card (Android)NV Verlag chartsOffline NOAA ChartsOther
Contactform - HelpdeskCommercial Shipping
This translation has been made to the best of our knowledge and belief. In case of any doubts or interpretation questions the original Dutch version is authoritative.
Privacy statement Stentec Software Ltd.
Stentec Software Ltd., located at Harinxmastrjitte 29, Heeg, the Netherlands, is responsible for processing personal data as presented in this privacy statement.
Contact information:
Harinxmastrjitte 29
8621BJ Heeg
the Netherlands
Telephone number: +31 515 443515
www.stentec.com
stentec@stentec.com
This privacy statement is prone to changes
when new developments give rise to this. The most actual privacy statement can always be found on www.stentec.com. We recommend you read this privacy statement regularly for the latest updates. The latest change date will always be shown in the privacy statement.
Last changes to this privacy statement were made on June 11th 2018:
Our privay statement has been updated conform the new AVG legislation.
1. Personal data processing
Stentec Software Ltd. processes your personal data while you make use of our services and/or when you provide us with them.
1.1 Persons younger than 16 years of age
Our website and/or services do not intend to collect data about persons below the age of 16 unless permission is granted from their parents or guardians. However, we can not check if a visitor is older than 16. We encourage parents to be involved in the online activities of their children, in order to prevent data about children being collected without parental consent. If you are convinced that we have collected personal information about a minor without parental consent, please contact us via stentec@stentec.com and we will remove the data.
1.2 Processed personal data
Below you will find an overview of all personal data we process and in which ways the data is stored.
Name, adress and residence. This data is stored when you:
create an account. This is applicable for our website and our own apps/software.
place an order. Applicable for orders via telephone, in store, per e-mail or in our online shop.
E-mail adress. This data is stored when you:
create an account. This is applicable for our website and our own apps/software.
place an order. Applicable for orders via telephone, in store, per e-mail or in our online shop.
subscribe to our news letter.
Your e-mail adress is used in combination with a password of your own choosing to log in to your account. You can log in while placing an order, when installing or updating your products or when logging in to Sail Simulators online platform. The licenses of your purchased products are connected to your account and thereby to your e-mail adress. It is your own responsibility to safely store your log in data.
Telephone number. This data is stored when you:
create an account. This is applicable for our website and our own apps/software.
place an order. Applicable for orders via telephone, in store, per e-mail or in our online shop.
Other personal data which you provide yourself via correspondence of via telephone.
Payment data. When you pay by:
one-off direct debit, you provide your bank account number via telephone or e-mail. We store your bank account number in our accounting software with the aim of correctly processing your order and faster service with future purchases.
1.3 When do we process personal data
While processing your payment
When you place an order we need certain personal data to deliver your order and inform you of the order status. The data is also needed for return or reparations. We ask you to provide us with your name, e-mail adress, adress, telephone number and, when needed for one-off direct debit, your bank account number. The data is required to execute the agreement that you have made with us. By law we must keep the data related to your order for 7 years.
While sending our news letter
On www.stentec.com you can sign up to our news letter. This can also be done when creating an account. The only data we store is your e-mail adress and, when provided, name. Signing off from our news letter can be done at the same location. When you sign off to our news letter your e-mail adress and name will be removed from our system.
When you have an account you will normally only receive product related e-mails. You have the option to sign in to extra (non product related) news letters. You can always change your preferences in your account settings.
When showing ranking in Sail Simulator 5
When you participate in Sail Simulators online platform, it's possible your country and username will be shown on www.sailsimulator.com. See 7.3 for more information.
2. For what purpose and on what basis personal data is processed
Stentec Software Ltd. processes your personal data for the following purposes:
For contacting you via telephone or e-mail when needed to provide you with our services.
To inform you about canges in our products and services.
To deliver our products and services.
Stentec Software Ltd. will also process personal data when obligated by law.
2.1 Automated decision-making
Stentec Software Ltd. does not take desicions based on automated processings about matters that can have (significant) consequences on people. These are decisions that are taken by computer programs or systems, without human interference (for example an employee of Stentec Software Ltd.).
2.2 Personal data storage
Stentec Software Ltd. uses the following software and systems in which personal data will (partially) be stored:
Exact Online: online accounting software. Stored are your name, adress, e-mail adress, telephone number(s) and, when provided, VAT number and bank account number. This will only be stored when you provide us with the data while placing an order.
Docdata: online payment system. When you place an order in our online shop from outside the Netherlands, or from within the Netherlands and choose to pay with ‘PayPal’, ‘Creditcard’ or ‘Money transfer’, the transaction will be processed by Docdata. Your name, adress and e-mail adress will be stored.
Mollie: online payment system. When you place an order in our online shop and choose to pay with ‘iDeal’, or when you order via telephone or e-mail, the transaction will be processed by Mollie. Your name and bank account number will be stored.
PayPal: online payment system. When you place an order in our online shop and choose to pay with PayPal the e-mail adress of your PayPal account will be stored in our PayPal account.
MyShop.com: online platform for offering our products. Your name, adress, e-mail adress, telephone number(s) and, when provided, your VAT number will be stored when you provide us with the data while placing an order.
Php-list: software for sending our news letters, marketing campaigns and announcements. Your name and e-mail adress are stored. See 1.3 for more information regarding the storage of your data in this software.
MailChimp: marketing platform for targeted mailings to (relatively) small groups.
Own online database: user accounts for navigation software and charts are stored on a server hosted by KPN Internedservices. Sail Simulators user accounts are stored on a server hosted by Hostbytes.
Google Analytics: When placing an order in our online shop Google Analytics uses your surfing behavior to improve our services.
Our own software and apps: We would like to draw your attention to the fact that the data that you enter or store in our software and apps are not stored by Stentec Software Ltd. Think of location data, dimensions of your ship, MMSI number, route planning, etc. This is only stored by the software and apps on your device.
2.3 Duration of storing personal data:
E-mail correspondence is stored indefinitely.
Billing information: By law we must keep the data related to your order for 7 years.
Account information will be stored up until the point you wish to delete the account.
3. Sharing personal data with third parties
Stentec Software Ltd. will not sell your personal data to third parties and will only provide this information when this is necessary for the execution of our agreement with you or to comply with a legal obligation.
It is possible your country and user name for your Sail Simulator account are shown on www.sailsimulator.com. See 7.3 for more information.
4. Use of cookies, or similar techniques
Stentec Software Ltd. only uses technical, functional and analytical cookies that do not infringe upon your privacy. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer, tablet or smartphone when you first visit this website. The cookies we use are necessary for the technical operation of the website and your ease of use. They ensure that the website works properly and remember, for example, your preferences. We can also optimize our website with them.
5. View, change or deleting personal data
You have the right to view, change or delete your personal data. You have the right to revoke your permission to process your personal data or object to the way your personal data is processed by Stentec Software Ltd. You also have the right of data portability. This means you can request a computer file with all available personal data Stentec has of you, which you can send to other organisations.
5.1 View, change or delete personal data yourself
Via your account on www.stentec.com you can view your personal data and purchased products. You can also change your personal data or request a removal of your account, and all available personal data. Your Sail Simulator account can be removed from within Sail Simulator itself.
5.2 Request
You can request to view, change, delete or receive your personal data, request to revoke your permission for process of your personal data or object to the way Stentec Software Ltd. processes your personal data via e-mail to stentec@stentec.com.
5.3 Secured personal data transfer
To make sure the request for personal data is made by yourself we request you send a copy of your identity card along with your request. In this copy blacken your foto, MRZ (machine readable zone), pasport number and citizen service number for protection of your own privacy.
5.4 Response time
We respond as quickly as possible, but no later than within four weeks, of your request.
5.5 File a complaint
Stentec Software Ltd. wants to inform you of the possibility to file a complaint with the national supervisor, the Dutch 'Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens'. This can be done via this link.
6. Protection of your personal data
Stentec Software Ltd. takes the protection of your data seriously and takes appropriate measures to prevent misuse, loss, unauthorized access, unwanted disclosure and unauthorized modification. If you have the impression that your personal data is not secure or there are indications of misuse, please contact us via our customer service or via stentec@stentec.com.
Stentec Software Ltd. has taken the following measures to protect your personal data:
Security software, such as a virus scanner and firewall.
Access to the stored (personal) data is limited only to personell who are authorized to do so.
7. About privacy issues within Stentec Software Ltd.
7.1 TeamViewer
TeamViewer is a help program and is used for sharing your screen with our helpdesk. This is only used when the user agrees with its use. Each time the user will be asked permission. Stentec Software Ltd. does not store any data. Stentec Software Ltd. wants to inform you that the name of your system will be shown when TeamViewer is used. The privacy statement for TeamViewer can be found on their own website, including the personal data they store themselves.
7.2 Photographs and other images
When you supply us with photographs or other images we will store these and may use these for internal use. When we want to use the images for external communication we will ask for your permission to do so.
7.3 Sail Simulator user name
When you want to participate in Sail Simulators online platform, you need to create a user account. This account consists of your e-mail adress password, country and user name. Your user name and country are used for the online platform. Other online users can see your user name and country when they are in the same online session as you are. On www.sailsimulator.com you can find all current sessions and the user with the best time for that specific session. You will also find a ranking system for all Sail Simulator users per class. It is possible your user name and country will appear in these lists.
DownloadsDocumentationAvailability GRIB filesFrequently asked questions - FAQ
WinGPS 5WinGPS Marine (Android)WinGPS Marine (iOS)Installation help
WinGPS 5 (Windows)WinGPS Marine (Android)Tips
Offline installation DKW charts (Windows)Installation ENC charts (Windows)Connecting SD card (Android)NV Verlag chartsOffline NOAA ChartsOther
Contactform - Helpdesk
Can we assist you?
We like to get in touch with you and give you personal advice or a free quotation.
Fill in the form
Terms and conditionsProduct activationPersonal advice & quotation formSign up for a workshopYour feedback & commentsStentec's websites:
wingpsmarine.comvaarkaartfriesemeren.nlwww.sailsimulator.com
Harinxmastrjitte 298621 BJ HEEGThe NetherlandsT +31 (0) 515 443515
Stay up to date! Sign up to our newsletter.
Sign up!
Copyright ©
Stentec Software. All rights reserved.
By using this website you acknowledge that you agree with our user agreement.
Privacy statement
